牢记
Remember...
你有早期的老年痴呆症
You have early stage Alzheimer's.
-你去度假了吗 -没有
- Have you gone to a vacation or something? - No.
-穆尼尔从来没有一个人吗？-不
- So Munir has never been alone? - No.
你忘给猫喂水了
You forgot to give water to your cat.
作为凶杀局唯一的女性员工感觉如何？
How does it feel to be the only woman working in an homicide bureau？
我从五十个女孩中选了你
I chose you from 50 girls.
真好啊
How nice.
因为我会忘记 所以我可以做任何我想做的事情 是吗？
Since I won't remember, I can do anything I want, is that so?
正是
Exactly.
你有远视眼镜吗？
Do you have farsighted glasses?
我今天遇到了一个名字叫内芙拉·埃尔马斯的女孩
I MET A GIRL TODAY. HER NAME WAS NEVRA ELMAS.
我是首席检查官托尔加·亚兹甘，您是哪位？
Chief Inspector Tolga Yazgan: Who is this?
我可能打错电话了
I must have dialed the wrong number.
这是穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔的家 小姐您找谁？
This is Mehmet Yurtgil's home, miss. Who were you calling?
我是他的女儿 我打电话给我父亲
I am his daughter. I was calling my dad.
他出什么事了吗？
Did something happen to him? Hello?
是的 小姐
Yes... I'm afraid so, miss.
不要越过警察线
DO NOT CROSS POLICE LINE
跟我走
Follow me.
-是谁干的？-我不知道
- Who did this, then? - I don't know.
是你干的吗？
You?
如果你知情不报，就是同谋 知道吗？
If you're hiding something, you'll be complicit. You know that?
我告诉过你 我不认识他
I told you. I don't know him.
也不认识他妻子
Neither his wife, nor him.
就这样吧
So be it.
不管谁杀了他 凶手一定认识你 然后……
Whoever killed him, must know you, then.
思考一下
Think about it.
你身边谁能做出这种事情？
Who is able to commit such a thing around you?
-没人 -你怎么知道？
- Nobody. - How do you know?
我了解身边的人
I know everybody.
他们谁都做不出这种事情
None of them could do such a bad thing.
这是谋杀
This is murder.
我？
Me?
打个比方
For instance.
你认为我可能会做出这种事吗？
You think I could do it?
不可能
No.
你知道你为什么会说不吗？
You know why you say no?
因为你害怕说是
Because you're afraid to say yes.
我为什么会害怕呢？
Why would I be afraid?
因为如果你说是 那我可以……
Because if you said yes, then I could...
在这条路上
Here, in the middle of this road,
把你杀掉
just shoot and kill you.
没有人知道
And nobody would really know.
你会害怕的 明白吗？
You'd be terrified. Understand?
这个世界上所有的邪恶都是我们不认识的人造成的
All the evil in this world is done by people we don't really know.
这就是为什么我们醒来时要做的第一件事是……
That's why the first thing we do when we wake up is...
自欺欺人
To fool ourselves.
所以我再问一次
So I'm asking again.
你身边有谁能做出这样的事情？
Who could have done such a thing?
我不知道
I have no idea.
长官
Chief...
阿加！阿加！求你了
Agah. Agah.
阿加! 阿加! 快停下！
Agah! Agah! Please!
阿加！
Agah!
阿加 你干嘛？
Agah, what have you done?
库尔德语
好了
Here you go.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
从租金中扣吧
Take that out of the rent.
几点了？
What time is it?
-1点10分 -好 还有时间
- Ten past one. - Good, there's time.
等等 阿加 您怎么会说库尔德语？
Sorry, Agah, how do you know Kurdish?
-库尔德语 为什么这么问？-你刚才说了
- Kurdish, why? - You just spoke it.
有时候她甚至不记得自己的名字
Sometimes she doesn't recall her own name.
你看不出来吗？
Can't you see her?
我妈妈能告诉你什么？
What could my mum tell you?
她跳舞跳的很好
She dances well, I heard.
-他们没有保姆吗？-当然有
- Didn't they have a caretaker? - Of course they had.
但是我爸
But my dad, bless him.
他是一个很难相处的人
He was a difficult person.
不管雇佣什么人都坚持不了三天
Whoever they hired left after three days.
一周前最后一个也走了
The last one left a week ago.
自从那以后就只有他们俩
They were alone since.
您有保姆的详细信息吗？
Do you have the details of the caretakers?
是的 我都有
Yes. I have everything.
我们一直都有联系
We spoke all the time.
我会把电话号码给你
I'll give the numbers.
我们现在可以离开了吗？
Can we leave now?
当然 您经历了艰难的一天
Sure. You've had quite a journey.
最后一件事
One last thing.
有人想杀你父亲吗？
Anybody who'd want to kill your father?
能想到谁吗？
Any name comes to mind?
谁想杀了他？
Who'd want to kill him?
小姐！你父亲是刑事法院的法官
Miss! Your father was a judge in criminal court.
他一定把什么人送进了监狱
He must have put somebody in prison.
但是他已经退休好几年了
But he retired years ago.
-自从您去马德里以来…… -奥莱！
- Since you're coming from Madrid... - Olé!
妈妈！
Mom!
这样说吧：
Let me tell you this way:
-斗牛士战斗到退休 -奥莱！
- Bullfighters fight until they retire. - Olé!
妈妈
Mom.
-但是公牛奋战到死 -奥莱！
- But bulls fight until they die. - Olé!
-奥莱！-妈妈！
- Olé! - Mom!
-奥莱！-妈妈
- Olé! - Mom.
我的车是用汽油的 不是柴油
MY CAR TAKES PETROL. NOT DIESEL!
好了先生
All right, sir.
-加满了吗？-是的 我加“满”了
- You fill it up? - Yes, I made it "full".
-汽油-是
- Petrol. - Yes.
好
Good.
告诉你件事
But I'll tell you something.
你不能让某件东西“满”
You don't make something full.
它不存在于任何语言中
It doesn't exist in any language.
不要再这样说了 好吗？
Don't use it again, okay?
最好忘记这个词
Better forget the word.
那不是很棒吗？
Wouldn't that be awesome?
如果我们忘记所有错误
If we forget everything wrong,
只记得正确的事情？
and only remember the correct things?
但是你不用担心
But don't you worry.
这里有很多错误 例如……
There's a lot of wrong in here. For example...
我以为女儿很幸福 但实际上并不是
I thought my daughter was happy, but she wasn't.
-先生200 -嗯？
- Sir, it's 200. - Huh?
200 您的账单
200. Your bill.
拿到楼上去
Take that upstairs.
我们已经飞了20个小时 坐车让我更累了
We've flown 20 hours, and the car ride tired me more.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
您像开出租车一样沿着风景优美的路线
You took the scenic route, like a cabbie.
常规路线这个时候会堵车
The usual route had rush hour.
这……
That's...
这就是原因
That's why.
您在这里住了多年了 怎么还这么糊涂？
You've been living here for years. How could you be confused?
我才没糊涂
I wasn't confused.
-你什么都没吃 -我不饿
- You didn't eat anything. - I'm not hungry.
你生病了吗？
Are you ill or something?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
爸 怎么回事 我刚刚离开了我自己的家
Dad, what the hell? I just left my bloody house.
你什么意思 生病了？
What do you mean, ill?
好吧 不能回头了吗？
Okay. Won't you go back?
-你要赶我们出去吗 -当然不是
- Are you kicking us out? - Of course not...
别担心 我们不会待久
Don't worry. We won't stay long.
-我什么也没说 -八号房间不是空的吗？
- I didn't say anything. - Isn't number eight empty anyway?
我们住在那里可以吧
We'll stay there.
我会找一份工作
I'll find myself a job.
可以给你你交租金 好吗？
I could pay rent, too. Okay?
爸
Dad...
我是说我带着我的孩子
I'm saying that I took my child,
我离开家来到这里
I left my house and come here.
你还问我能不能回头？
You're asking me if I'm... I'm not going back!
-好的 不要 -不能了！
- Okay, don't. - I'm not!
好啦 不要走
All right, don't go.
没关系
Never mind.
我受不了了
I can't take it anymore.
-我不能 -我求你了 祖哈尔
- I just can't. - I beg of you, Zuhal.
爸爸！
Daddy!
拜托 祖哈尔 我的宝贝
Please, Zuhal. My baby.
-爸爸 我现在该怎么办？-你也会让你儿子也伤心的
- What will I do now, daddy? - You'll make him sad, too.
但是有人刚租了八号房
But I just rented number eight.
他刚搬进去
He just moved in.
刑事和解
CRIMINAL COURTS OF PEACE
新法官访问地区总督
THE NEW JUDGE VISITED THE DISTRICT GOVERNOR
跟实验室沟通了吗？
Speak with the lab yet?
嗯 他们正在处理
I did. They're working on it.
我想看看他以前在哪里工作
I was just trying to see where he previously worked.
也许我能发现一些东西
Maybe I could see something.
尸检后他们会打电话 不要离开
They'll call after the autopsy.Don't go anywhere.
-你不去吗？ -我是谁啊？
- Won't you go in? - Who am I?
毕竟有你在呢
We have you, after all.
把文件放在我的桌子上 我会教你怎么看
But leave the file on my desk so I'll teach you to read.
也要教她怎么写
Teach her to write, too.
你见过我做事做一半的时候吗？
Ever seen me half-ass something?
我当然会教她
Of course I will.
这是我的工作
It's my job.
是哦
True.
我会写
See, I can write.
不用教我
Don't have to teach me that.
我今天遇到一个笨蛋 他的名字叫菲鲁兹
I MET AN OAF TODAY. HIS NAME WAS FIRUZ.
-他睡觉了吗-是的
- Did he go to sleep? - Yeah.
床可以吗？
Is the bed all right?
可以 但是
It is, it is but...
我希望这里一切都好
I wish it could be all right up here.
-那是我的随身听吗？-恩
- Is that my Walkman? - Uh-huh.
-还能用吗？-可以
- Does it still work? - It does.
爸爸 电视在哪？
Where's the TV, dad?
我给了需要它的人
I gave it to someone who needed it.
-你不看吗？-我已经看了四十年了
- Don't you watch it? - I watched forty years of it.
-好的 晚安 -晚安 亲爱的
- Okay, good night then. - Good night, sweetie.
-祖哈尔 -什么？
- Zuhal. - What?
那个碗里有备用钥匙
Take the spare key in that bowl.
给德瓦也拿一把
I gave one to Deva, too.
喂？
Yes?
好的
Okay.
我二十分钟就到
I'll be there in twenty minutes.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
日记
DEAR DIARY
我只相信她 因为内芙拉了解我
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.
帖木儿 你在吗？我是内芙拉
Timur, are you in? It's me, Nevra.
来了
I'm coming...
欢迎
Welcome.
我们之前在电话是沟通过 但从未没见过面
We've spoken before, but never met in person.
是的 嗨
Yes, hi.
没有人尊重这里的人 他们都直接闯进来
Nobody has any respect to the people in here. They barge in.
这就是我锁门的原因
That's why I lock the door.
我还有其他事情要做 所以迟到了
I had something else to do. That's why I was late.
你来的刚刚好
You're just in time.
我刚才在休息
I was on a break.
你会习惯的
You'll get used to it.
人们习惯了死人
People get used to the dead.
他们不能伤害任何人
They can't harm anybody.
我是说不会再伤害了
Not anymore, I mean.
要学着适应
The thing is to get used to the living.
那才是困难的部分
That's the hard part.
你要喝点什么吗我可以煮咖啡
You want something to drink? I can make some coffee.
如果你也要喝的话……
If you're making some for yourself.
他的额头上曾贴着一个有您名字的标签是吗？
Did he really have a label on his forehead with your name on it?
-是的 -是连环杀手的风格
- Yeah. - A serial killer situation.
是的
It is.
但是 在这个国家当然很难找到
But, difficult to find one in this country of course.
土耳其没有连环杀手
There are no serial killers in Turkey.
然而有人却在大肆杀戮
There are people who go on a killing spree.
好了……
Now...
这是近距离射击
The shot was in point-blank range.
两三米之内
Less than two or three meters.
没有挣扎的迹象
No signs of a struggle.
死亡时间不超过96个小时
He's been dead for 96 hours at the most.
伤口只有一处 7.65mm子弹
There's one entry wound, 7.65.
咖啡加牛奶还是加糖？
Any sugar or milk in your coffee?
不用了
Nope.
喂？
Hello?
好的
Okay.
我很快就到
I'll be there soon.
是实验室打来的 他们匹配到了指纹信息
It was the lab. They found a match for the prints.
真的吗？你能找到他了吗？
Seriously? You found him then?
谢谢你的咖啡
Thanks for the coffee.
回头见
See you later.
法官大人
Your honor.
您什么时候可以给大麻合法化？
When will you legalize this?
你能联系到主管检察官吗？
Can you reach the prosecutor in charge?
我们需要逮捕令
We'll need a warrant of arrest.
我确信我已经抓到凶手了
I believe I'm getting the hang of this.
真的
I really do.
我希望梅布鲁雷能看到
I wish Mebrure could see this.
我们彼此十分相爱
We loved each other so.
许多美好的回忆
So many memories.
我唯一的希望
My only hope
是在我忘掉所有人之前就死了
is to die before I forget them all.
但是你怎么知道呢？
But how would you know that? Right?
不要告诉我你也爱过
Don't tell me that you loved too.
你的不是爱而是仇恨
Yours isn't love. It's rancor.
你不会带着怨恨去爱
You don't love with rancor.
-这是凶手的家吗？-是的
- Is that the man's home? - Yeah.
-他有武器 -应该是的
- He's armed, of course. - Probably, yes.
我们进去抓到他 然后离开
We'll go in, pick him up, then leave.
可怜
Pity.
你都浪费了
You wasted it all.
你老婆很爱你
Your wife obviously loved you so much.
竭尽全力为你打造一个家
Moved heaven and earth to make a home for you.
你却把她当成理所当然
You took her for granted.
我可以原谅任何事
I forgive everything...
但我不会原谅任何将妻子视为理所当然的人
But I don't forgive anyone who takes his wife for granted.
我必须坦率地说对不起
I have to be frank. I'm sorry.
别这样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
我本来可以选别人的
I could have picked somebody else.
但是你罪孽深重
But you're very guilty.
而且你也没有受到相应的惩罚
And you weren't properly punished.
什么八年？
What's eight years?
“因表现良好……
"Unjust provocation...
获得减刑” 减刑后又减刑
Time off for good behavior." Mitigation after mitigation.
他们应该给你一枚奖章
They could have given you a medal too.
我已经看过了庭审记录
I've read the trial records.
他们给予了适当的考虑
They gave proper consideration
但他们没有进行适当的惩罚
but they didn't deal proper retribution.
因此
Therefore...
你将在这里受到真正的惩罚
You're getting your real punishment in here.
你知道你的惩罚是什么吗？
You know what your punishment is?
你将成为我杀人的武器
You'll be my murder weapon.
很好 不是吗？
Good, isn't it?
安全 罪犯不在这里 收队
Clear. Perp is not in. We're moving out.
我们进去搜查
We're going in. We'll conduct a search.
那是萨利
That's Salih.
他是个不错的卡车司机
He's a decent lorry driver.
他还帮我们搬过家
He even helped us move,
但梅布鲁雷非常挑剔
and Mebrure is extraordinarily fussy.
你将会把萨利杀掉
You'll be killing Salih!
来吧
Come on.
手指伸出来
Give me your finger.
别难为人了 我的后背酸痛 快点
Don't be difficult, my back is aching up. Come on.
上一次真的太容易了 手指伸出来
It was so easy the last time. Give me your finger.
听好了
Look.
如果你表现好
If you'll be nice,
我会用另一种方式给你戴手铐 那样会舒服很多 好吗？
I'll handcuff you the other way. It'll be more comfortable. Deal?
同意吗？来吧 手指给我
Agreed? Come. Give me your finger.
来吧给我
Come on, give it to me.
你在生我的气
You're mad at me.
但是如果换了别人会把你手指切掉的
But anyone else would've cut it off.
大功告成
We're done.
当然 只服刑是不行的
Of course, only serving a sentence wouldn't do.
你需要改过自新
You need rehabilitation.
没有悔过 服刑有什么用呢？
What's a sentence good for without rehabilitation?
没用
Nothing.
每个人喜欢都收集东西
Everyone collects something.
这是我的收藏
And this is my collection.
我还有很多 但这些对你有特殊意义
I have a lot more, but this is special for you.
别告诉别人……
Keep this between us...
这些是我从案卷里偷来的
I pinched these from case files, back in the day.
你好好看看
You look at them well,
想想你所做过的恶心事
and think of the nasty things that you've done.
好吗？
Okay?
所有的东西都收拾好 伴随着你自己
All things packed away, Along with yourself.
记忆零散 到房间 到处都是
Memories are scattered, To the room, everywhere.
我习惯的香水不再存在
The perfume I'm used to Is no longer there.
你
You.
你的笑容从屋子的角落消失了
Your smile has faded From the nooks of the house.
孤独很痛苦 请不要离开我
Loneliness is bitter.Please don't leave me.
我们一起爱过这个无色的世界
We have loved this Colorless world together.
你
You.
我的女人
My woman.
记得在街对面
Remember when In the street across.
我们有生以来第一次亲吻
We have kissed For the first time in my life.
锁定拥抱一个春天的早晨
Locked in embrace One spring morning.
你
You.
灯灭了屋子里一片漆黑
The lights are off The house is under dark.
我们温暖的阳光下的房子现在变得寒冷
Our warm sunlit house Has now grown cold.
夜永远继续我不断哭泣
Nights go on forever I keep on weeping.
您
You.
我的女人
My woman.
-天啊！-爸爸
- Oh dear! - Dad!
抱歉 亲爱的 我……
So sorry, sweetie. I...
你起来了吗
You're up? Come in.
我当然起来了 你整晚都敲门
Of course I'm up. You knocked the door all night.
祖哈尔！德瓦说话了！
Zuhal! Deva speaks!
德瓦第一次对我说话！
Deva spoke to me for the first time!
干得好 德瓦！早上好 德瓦！
Good job, Deva! Good morning, Deva!
-早上好-享受早餐 德瓦
- Good morning. - Enjoy your breakfast, Deva.
来吧亲爱的 一切都准备好了
Come sweetie. Everything's ready.
爸爸 我必须出去
I won't stay, daddy. I have to go out.
我要去我以前的公司
There was this Onat in my old company.
昨天我给他写了一封求职信
I wrote to him yesterday about a job.
-你才刚到这 亲爱的-是的
- You just arrived, sweetie. - Yes.
但是我们必须尽快安顿下来
But we have to settle down as soon as possible.
我还要去德瓦的学校
I'll drop by Deva's school, too.
我希望学校那边不要因为是期中阶段让我难堪
I hope they don't give me a rough time, with it being mid-semester, and all.
坐下喝茶 我煮咖啡给你
Sit down, have some tea. I'll make you coffee.
等一下我去拿
I'll get something later.
祖父和孙子 你们会玩得很开心的
You'll have a good time, grandfather and grandson.
当然 我会带他到处转转
Sure. I'll show Deva around.
我可以吃些面包吗 德瓦？
May I have some bread, Deva?
如果你愿意的话 可以一个人呆着
You're free to be alone, if you want.
其实 你可以一个人呆着
Actually, you're free to be alone.
我昨晚睡得很香
I slept like a log last night.
内芙拉.
Nevra.
抱歉 长官 我睡着了
Sorry, Chief. I dozed off.
昨晚我们确认了嫌犯并且搜查了他的房子
We ID'd the perp and raided his house last night...
好的 好的 放松
Okay, okay. Calm down.
我都听说了
I've heard everything.
回家睡一下
Go home, get some sleep.
下午回来
Come back in the afternoon.
但是你必须把昨晚的事告诉菲鲁兹
But you had to inform Firuz last night.
-事情发生的太快了 -于事无补
- It all happened so quickly. - The damage is done.
你现在回家吧 好吗？
You go home now, okay?
-晚安-早上好
- Good night. - Good morning.
阿加?
Agah?
-阿加 你好吗？-谢谢 鲁斯特姆 你怎么样？
- Agah, how are you? - Thanks, Rustem. You?
很好 知足了 这小伙子是谁？
Fine, can't complain. Who's the lad?
我的孙子 他昨天和他妈妈一起来的
My grandson. He's arrived yesterday with his mother.
好消息啊 你认识你的祖父吗？
Joyous news. You know your grandfather?
他是杀手
He's a killer.
你已经把乐器弄死了
You've killed the instrument.
你刺了鼓！
You stabbed the drum!
但是谢谢你了 那鼓真的很烦人
But thanks. They were being obnoxiously loud.
这回我们安心了
We'll have some peace of mind.
回头见
See you later.
好吧
Okay then.
-你刺坏了鼓吗？-什么？
- You stabbed a drum? - What?
哦 没什么大不了的
Oh, it's not a big deal.
需要我把你送到什么地方吗？
Could I drop you off somewhere?
不 我可以自己走
Nah, I can go myself.
好的
Okay.
祝你玩得开心
Have fun, then.
你也是
You too.
-好的 待会见-很好
- Okay, see you later - Fine
卡车司机萨利
Salih the lorry driver.
我知道你喜欢什么
I know what you like.
我没有预约就来了 对不起
I dropped in without an appointment, sorry.
简历发过来就好
Sending your CV would have been fine,
他们有特殊要求
but Onat specially requested.
你住在澳大利亚吗？
You lived in Australia?
是的 在悉尼住了四年
Yes, four years in Sydney.
我们刚回来
We just came back.
-为什么笑？-我不知道
- Why the laugh? - I don't know.
大家都很想去那里 每个人都想离开这
People kill to be there, everyone's trying to leave.
但是你回来了
But you've come back.
你是我们以前的雇员吗？
You were a former employee of ours?
对 但是
Yes, but...
我的意思是我曾在这里工作 但是情况发生了很大变化
I mean... I worked here. But things changed a lot.
你每天都来找我 就像是你的工作一样 才给100？
You come to me every day like it's your job, and you leave a 100?
滚蛋
Go away.
这个房间没变
This room hasn't changed.
还是一样
Still the same.
恭喜啦
Congratulations.
人力资源部无人问津
No one drops by Human Resources,
你记得很清楚
but you seem to remember it well.
不 这是我的房间
No, this was my room.
椅子也一样
And the chair's the same, too.
那曾经是我的椅子
That used to be my chair.
这是其他部门的吗？
This used to be another department?
没有
No.
是人力资源部
It was Human Resources.
我曾坐在你现在的位置
I was at your position.
真的？
Really?
小姐
Miss...
你是来接管我工作的吗？
Are you here to take my job away?
不是
No.
我以为你可能需要一些帮助
I thought that maybe you'd need some help.
你怎么可以忘记加油？
How could you forget about filling up?
-进来 -医生 我很抱歉……
- Come in. - Doctor, I'm so sorry...
-医生 这很重要 -先生 对不起
- Doctor, it's important. - Sir, excuse me.
阿加 请进来 冷静一下
Agah, come in. Please, calm down.
没事的
We're okay.
我必须告诉你些事情
I have to tell you.
女厕所
LADIES' ROOM
内芙拉.
Nevra.
如果你再做这样的事 我会让你后悔的 你听到了吗？
If you pull anything like this again, I'll make you sorry. You hear me?
如果你继续威胁我的话 我就不出去了
If you have more of those threats, I'll stay in here.
?？
Huh?
见鬼！
Shit!
杀手留下的信息
MESSAGE FROM THE KILLER
我该怎么办？
What will I do?
如果我能够忘记了如此重要的事情
If I'm already forgetting such vital things...
您认为我应该更改处方吗？
Should I change prescriptions, you think?
我有时也会忘记加油
I forget to fill up sometimes.
不要对自己要求这么苛刻
Don't be so hard on yourself.
没有人能完全无误地记住每件事
No one can remember everything completely and without error.
用完了汽油或者柴油 无所谓的
You'll run out of petrol or gas!
重要的是要保持冷静
What's important is to stay calm.
并找到解决方案
And to find a solution.
你不能让任何不寻常的事影响到你
You can't let anything out of the ordinary get to you.
有时最好的计划就是没有计划
Sometimes the best plan is to not have a plan.
做个决定
Make your mind up.
我到底要不要做计划？
Do I have a plan, or not?
要做 继续做好你的计划
Do. Do have your plan.
如果到了不用做计划的时候我会告诉你
I'm telling you to make changes when necessary.
我知道 我还不那么老
I get it. I'm not that old.
那就没问题了
We're settled, then.
所以我不需要一直都有计划
So I don't need to have a plan all the time.
不用
No.
适应自己
Adapt yourself.
要是我们能提前计划一切就好了……
If only we could plan everything in advance...
运气也是不容忽视的
There's luck to be reckoned with.
有时候你必须相信自己的运气
Sometimes you have to trust your luck,
有时你只需要接受它
and sometimes you just have to accept it.
还有一件很重要的事情
There's something else that's important.
我曾经在西罗皮法院工作了三年
I used to work in the Silopi Court of Justice for three years.
我以为我忘记了
I thought I forgot,
但我没有忘记说库尔德语
but I didn't forget to speak Kurdish.
没有自动取款机 我们找了一个上午都没找到
No ATMs... We've been looking all morning. Nothing!
-也没看到转弯 -但是大家都看到这个了
- We can't see the turn. - But everybody's seeing this.
-怎么会这样？-我听说了
- How could this happen? - I've heard about it. I saw it.
-但这就是他的工作方式 -他是谁？
- But that's how he works. - Who is he?
那个卑鄙的记者阿提斯 阿尔巴伊
That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
但是我没有生他的气
But I'm not mad at him.
我没有生他的气！
I'm not mad at him!
我对那个白痴生气
I'm mad at the idiot...
我对那个傻瓜生气
I'm mad at the fool
那个用这条消息换了几百块钱的傻B！
that sells this piece for a handful of money!
将会有一名检察官到这来 我们走着瞧！
They'll send an inspector, and then we'll see!
那就是要发生的事
That's what's going to happen.
我们没有其他镜头吗？
Don't we have any other footage?
没了 长官
No, Chief.
我不想让德瓦浪费这一年的时间
I don't want Deva to lose a year.
我懂
I see.
这次搬家已经给他造成了很大影响
This relocation is already taking its toll on him.
当然
Of course.
您觉得怎么样呢？
So what do you say?
您可以安排他来学校吗？
You think something could be arranged? Could you take him?
校长您觉得怎样？能招他吗？
What do you say, headmaster? Could you enroll him?
我记得德瓦
I remember Deva now
真是个好孩子
Such a sweet kid. Had excellent grades.
他以前弹什么乐器 是吉他吗？
He used to play something, too. What was it, a guitar?
-是小提琴 -是的
- It was a violin. - Yes, it was.
他还在练琴吗？
Does he still play?
不了
No, I'm afraid not.
他不再练琴了
He doesn't play anymore.
谁知道了 也许我们会让他再练起来
Who knows, maybe we'll have him pick it up again.
那您愿意招他进来吗？
Will you enroll him, then?
老实说 我们学校真的没有名额了
To be honest, we don't have a place at the school.
但我会为你儿子破个例
But I'll do an exception for your son.
-谢谢 -但是
- Thank you. - But...
学费金额会有所不同
The payment will be different this time.
由于是期中入学 因此没有学费折扣
Since you're here mid-year, you won't get the discount.
我相信这应该不是问题吧？
I trust that's not a problem?
-你有烟吗？-不
- You have a cigarette? - No.
有钱吗？
You have money?
没有
No.
那你要怎么泡她？
How will you screw her, then?
她是个妓女
She's a straight up whore.
你给她拉皮条吗？
And are you her pimp?
我可以拉
I could be.
好吧
Okay.
谁给你拉皮条？
And who is your pimp?
你说什么？老子干死你！
What did you say? I'll fuck you up.
别看着我
Stop looking at me.
回来
Come here.
站住！
Stop!
回来！
Come here!
阿加 别浪费时间了
Agah, don't waste your time.
电梯又坏了 我给修理工打过电话 但他很忙 会很晚才来
It's out of order again. I spoke to the mechanic, but he'll come late. He was busy.
真倒霉
I have the worst luck.
-鲁斯特姆 -什么事 先生
- Rustem. - Yes, sir.
-随便说个数字 -您在玩数字游戏吗？
- Give me a number. - Are you playing the numbers?
-随便说一个 -如果赢了 我们就是合作伙伴
- Just give me one. - If it wins, we're partners.
-39 -不得超过27
- 39. - Has to be up to 27.
如果高于27 那不是一个幸运数字 对吧？
If it's above 27, it's not a lucky number, huh?
那好 24
Okay then, 24.
-不 26 -想好再说
- No, 26. - Make your mind up.
这样的话……
In that case...
-你是谁？-我来自西姆迪报纸
- Who am I speaking to? - I'm from the newspaper Simdi.
我是阿提斯 阿尔巴伊 你好吗 内芙拉？
Ates Arbay. How do you do, Nevra?
您在哪里找到这个号码？
Where did you find this number?
我知道你很生气 但是……
I know you're angry, but...
你为什么要采访我？
Why'd you want to have an interview with me?
-他们已经问过所有问题了 -是的
- They asked me everything. - Yes.
我知道他们问过 但是
I know they did, but...
他们没有问你正确的问题
they didn't ask you the right questions.
那这次采访对我有什么好处呢？
What is that gift you have for me that'll be so useful?
一些存在于外太空的信息
Some information that exists in the outer space.
但是不接受采访就不能给你
But you can't have it without an interview.
我来评估一下
I'll be the judge of that.
我要看看你到底有什么消息
I'll have to see what you have.
看看我们能做什么
And we'll see what we can do.
今晚10:30我们在叛乱酒吧见面
Let's meet. Be at Isyan Sanayi after 10:30, tonight.
叛乱酒吧？
Isyan Sanayi?
-德瓦？-是我 妈妈
- Deva? - It's me, mom.
-我喝了一点酒 -我知道
- I... drank a bit. - I know.
不要告诉你父亲
Don't tell your father.
好 睡吧
Okay, go to sleep.
好吗 不要告诉他
Okay. Just, don't tell him.
不要说我喝酒了
Don't say that I drank.
不要告诉他 好吗亲爱的？
Don't tell him, okay sweetie?
你怎么开车的？
What are you doing?
你想撞死我吗？
What is this? Do you want to run me over?
嘿
Hey.
-你差点撞到我 -别生气
- You were going to hit me. - Don't get mad.
我不行了
I'm out.
天意啊
Goodness.
-你喜欢音乐吗？-你在浪费时间
- Do you like the music? - You're wasting your time.
没有所谓的“DJ音乐” 永远不会有
There's no such thing as 'DJ music'. Never will be.
别跟别人说这句话
Don't tell anybody.
谁泄漏了消息 阿提斯？
Who leaked the news, Ates?
我会永远记得你第一次叫我的名字
I'll always remember this first time you said my name.
你问了一个我不可能回答的问题
In a moment you asked me something impossible.
不要这样
Don't do it.
可以把消息告诉我了吗？
Can I have my gift now?
我不知道 可以吗？
I don't know. Can you?
先喝酒吧
First the firewater.
-多少钱一克？-什么？
- What do you pay for a gram? - What?
可卡因 你要付多少钱？
Cocaine, I mean. How much do you pay?
我敢打赌他们对你要价很高
They're overcharging you, I bet.
不用担心
Don't worry.
你只是外太空的一个信息
You're just an information in an outer space.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
您只是经销商手机中的一个号码 懂吗？
You're just a number in a dealer's mobile phone. See?
这里有电脑吗？
Is there a computer I could use?
你可以在这工作 不会有人来打扰你
You could work here without interruption.
我要回去工作了
I have to be back on duty.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
内芙拉.
Nevra.
-我会有麻烦吗？-有的
- Will I be in trouble? - You will.
如果这里有毒贩的话 会有的
If there's a dealer like that somewhere, you will.
很高兴认识你 内芙拉
Glad to meet you, Nevra.
我也是
So am I.
-我们现在在录音吗？-是的
- Are we recording right now? - Yes, we are.
-副本会给我一份 对吧 -可以
- You'll give me a copy, right? - I said okay.
我给你看一张清单 卡尔迪兰法院大楼已经被烧毁
I'll read you a list. The courthouse at Cald?ran has burnt down.
塞菲尔皮纳尔法院也是如此
So did the one at Sefilp?nar.
还有坎布拉法院
So did the one at Kambura.
但是你跟我说这些事情都与你无关
But you tell me you had nothing to do with them.
不 我怎么有时间做所有这些事情？
No. How could I have the time for all of that?
一定有别人在做这些事
Some other brothers must have taken care of them.
你是如何开始的？
How did you begin?
有这个人 他在法庭上有一个档案
There was this man, and he had a file in the courthouse.
但这一切都是诽谤
But it's all slander.
他们捏造了所有的指控
They made up all the accusations.
我不能忍受这样的不公正
And I couldn't stand for any injustice like that.
你知道 我是那里的法警
I'm a bailiff there, as you know.
我把所有东西都烧掉了
I burned the whole thing down.
正义最终会占上风的 你明白吗？
So that justice prevails in the end, you know?
天啊
Oh, man.
天啊！
Oh, man!
你为什么要杀我？
Why did you shoot me, man?
我对你做了什么？
What did I do to you?
你根本没变纳伊姆汉
You haven't changed at all, Naimhan.
一点也没变
Not at all.
你以前也是这样
You used to be like this.
总是喝醉
Always drunk.
你就一点都不担心你的肝脏吗？
Aren't you afraid of what you'll do to your liver?
反正你不会长寿
You wouldn't live long, anyway.
你应该活得更久一点
You would live a bit longer, I suppose.
今天不是你的日子
It wasn't your day.
但情况就是这样了
But so it goes.
我没汽油了
I ran out of petrol.
我忘了加满油箱
I forgot to fill up the tank.
然后你突然出现
And you suddenly appeared.
我完全没想到
I wasn't expecting it at all.
但是医生就是这样说的
But the doctor said so.
运气确实不容小觑
Luck really does have to be reckoned with.
跟踪别人很难
It's hard to follow people.
很难
Very hard.
整日追逐他们
Pursue them all day,
在他们的房子外面等
wait outside their place.
他们做什么 他们去哪里？
What do they do, where do they go?
他们什么时候睡觉 什么时候醒？
When do they go to sleep, when do they wake up?
就像工作
It's like having a job.
真的
Really.
老哥
Man.
你从哪认识我的？
Where do you know me from?
我们在哪见过面吗？
Where did we meet?
你是哪里人？
Where are you from?
坎布拉
Kambura.
那就是我认识你的地方
And that's where I know you from.
别这样
Don't do it, man...
我求求你 别杀我
I beg you, don't, man.
我什么都没做 纳伊姆汉
I'm not doing anything, Naimhan.
我什么都没做
I haven't done anything.
是你做了
You did it.
你和他们
You and them.
你们所有人
All of you.
你不该做的
You shouldn't have.
我只相信她 因为内芙拉了解我
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.